<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>hypernormalized</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io</link><description>Reduction, systems, and the tension between order and entropy.</description><language>en</language><item><title>Order and Entropy</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/order-and-entropy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My practice usually leans towards order. I look at Ikko Tanaka—radical reduction, geometric purity, the grid as a silent, invisible hand. It feels safe. It feels correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then there is Tadanori Yokoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Tanaka is the grid, Yokoo is the explosion that happens when the grid can no longer contain the pressure. His work is a &amp;ldquo;death statement&amp;rdquo; to the self—a psychedelic vomit of personal memory, cultural taboo, and pop art. It is chaotic, but it is not random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This distinction matters for generative art. We often use &lt;code&gt;Math.random()&lt;/code&gt; to introduce &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;chaos&amp;rdquo; into a system. But randomness is just white noise. It has no history. Yokoo’s chaos comes from &lt;em&gt;memory&lt;/em&gt;—specific, loaded, heavy symbols crashing into each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To move beyond simple geometric exercises, the system needs more than just noise. It needs a memory bank. It needs to pull from a history, even if that history is fabricated. Chaos with context is narrative. Chaos without context is just static.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/order-and-entropy/</guid></item><item><title>Absurdity as Structure</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/absurdity-as-structure/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Shigeo Fukuda said that design needs &amp;ldquo;30% dignity, 20% beauty, and 50% absurdity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That ratio feels correct for code, too. We often optimize for dignity (clean architecture, stability) or beauty (elegant output, smooth motion), but we forget the absurdity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absurdity isn&amp;rsquo;t just chaos. In Fukuda’s work—like the famous sculpture that casts a shadow of a motorcycle from a pile of junk—the absurdity is highly structured. It’s a trick that relies on precise alignment. It only works because the underlying logic is rigorous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In generative systems, &amp;ldquo;absurdity&amp;rdquo; usually just means &lt;code&gt;Math.random()&lt;/code&gt;. But true absurdity requires context. It requires a system that &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; makes sense, but twists the logic just enough to break the viewer’s expectation. A grid that refuses to align. A loop that counts backward. A physics simulation where gravity works sideways, but only for blue objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dignity provides the frame. Beauty provides the hook. But absurdity provides the reason to keep looking.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/absurdity-as-structure/</guid></item><item><title>The Vital Element</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/the-vital-element/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at Kazumasa Nagai&amp;rsquo;s later work — the &lt;em&gt;LIFE&lt;/em&gt; series specifically. There&amp;rsquo;s a severe shift that happens in his career, moving from strict geometric abstraction into something raw and hand-drawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What interests me is not just the stylistic change, but the motivation. He talks about striving to &amp;ldquo;deliver what I perceive from nature through my hands.&amp;rdquo; The work is about energy. &amp;ldquo;Strength to live.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a reminder that precision isn&amp;rsquo;t the only form of rigor. There is a kind of structural integrity in organic forms, too. In generative work, we often obsess over the grid, the perfect rule, the clean loop. Nagai’s creatures — these strange, etched animals — feel inevitable in a different way. They feel grown, not built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to find that feeling in code. Not by simulating brush strokes (which always feels fake), but by finding algorithms that have that same nervous energy. Systems that wobble.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/the-vital-element/</guid></item><item><title>Nine Post Cards</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/nine-post-cards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First study is up: &lt;a href="/studies/nine-post-cards/"&gt;Nine Post Cards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with Yoshimura&amp;rsquo;s album of the same name — ambient piano pieces composed for a museum, meant to exist in the background of a space rather than the foreground of your attention. I wanted to see what that philosophy looks like as a generative visual system. Simple forms, slow movement, a narrow palette. Something that lives on the page without asking anything of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every reload is a different composition. Same system, different moment. Like looking out the same window on different days.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/nine-post-cards/</guid></item><item><title>Opening</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/opening/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a space for working in the open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make things with code, mostly generative — systems that produce visual output through simple rules and structured randomness. The work lives somewhere between design and art, though I&amp;rsquo;m not precious about the distinction. What matters is the process: defining a system, watching it run, finding the moments where order starts to come apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name &lt;em&gt;hypernormalized&lt;/em&gt; comes from that tension. Systems that appear stable, coherent, inevitable — until you look at the seams. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the seams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find two kinds of things. The &lt;strong&gt;log&lt;/strong&gt; is writing — notes on process, technique, ideas I&amp;rsquo;m working through. &lt;strong&gt;Studies&lt;/strong&gt; are visual — generative sketches, usually built with p5.js, each one an experiment with a specific constraint or question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing here is finished. That&amp;rsquo;s the point. A studio is not a gallery.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/opening/</guid></item><item><title>Nine Post Cards</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/nine-post-cards/</link><description>&lt;div class="sketch-container" id="sketch-nine-post-cards"&gt;&lt;script src="/js/nine-post-cards.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1982, Hiroshi Yoshimura composed &lt;em&gt;Music for Nine Post Cards&lt;/em&gt; for the Hara Museum of Contemporary Art in Tokyo. The pieces weren&amp;rsquo;t meant to be listened to so much as lived alongside — sound shaped by the architecture it inhabited, drifting like light across a white wall. The Japanese called this &lt;em&gt;kankyō ongaku&lt;/em&gt;: environmental music. Art that accompanies rather than commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep coming back to this idea. Ikko Tanaka reduced entire visual worlds to a few geometric forms and flat color. Yoshimura reduced music to single piano notes and silence. Both understood that restraint isn&amp;rsquo;t absence — it&amp;rsquo;s attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sketch tries to work in that space. Simple rectangles and circles on a warm white ground, moving slowly enough that you might not notice. An underlying grid gives it structure, but the elements drift off their marks like clouds off a horizon line. Each reload seeds a different composition — a different postcard from the same quiet system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The palette is deliberately narrow. Warm grays, transparency, and a muted ochre that appears sparingly, the way a single sustained note might surface in one of Yoshimura&amp;rsquo;s pieces. Nothing demands your attention. It just runs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/nine-post-cards/</guid></item></channel></rss>