<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>hypernormalized</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io</link><description>Reduction, systems, and the tension between order and entropy.</description><language>en</language><item><title>The Visual Language of Rhythm</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/the-visual-language-of-rhythm/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Toshihiro Katayama’s work exists at a specific intersection: graphic design, sculpture, and environmental art. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His compositions are often compared to modern jazz. Like jazz, his work is built on a &amp;ldquo;grid&amp;rdquo; of sensibility and skill, but it finds its life through rhythms and patterns that feel improvised within that structure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katayama taught &amp;ldquo;Visual Language&amp;rdquo; at Harvard for decades. He didn&amp;rsquo;t teach ego; he taught the fundamental building blocks of perception. He used line and space not just to communicate information, but to create a three-dimensional woven aesthetic on a two-dimensional plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his 1968 poster for the exhibition &lt;em&gt;Thonet: Form from Process&lt;/em&gt;, he used graduating line weights and a 12-column grid to create a sense of movement and structural depth that mirrored the bentwood processes of the chairs themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, Katayama’s link to jazz is the most compelling bridge. Jazz relies on the tension between the strict time of the rhythm section and the syncopation of the soloist. In generative work, we often struggle to find that balance—the code is either too rigid or too chaotic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katayama shows us that the rhythm itself can be the structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visual study in progress: &amp;ldquo;Syncopation No. 1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/the-visual-language-of-rhythm/</guid></item><item><title>Visual Kankyō Ongaku</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/visual-kankyo-ongaku/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hiroshi Yoshimura’s &lt;em&gt;Green&lt;/em&gt; (1986) uses FM synthesis—cold, crisp digital tones—to evoke warmth and growth. It belongs to the genre of &lt;em&gt;kankyō ongaku&lt;/em&gt; (environmental music), designed not to demand attention like a concert performance, but to enrich the space it inhabits, like furniture or light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In generative art, we often chase the spectacular. We want complex emergent behaviors that dazzle the viewer, demanding engagement. But what if we aimed for the environmental?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;visual kankyō ongaku&amp;rdquo; would be an algorithm that sits quietly in a browser tab. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t scream for interaction. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t explode with color. It breathes. It shifts imperceptibly over hours, like light moving across a wall. It acknowledges that the screen is not just a stage, but an environment we live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the goal isn&amp;rsquo;t to simulate nature, but to simulate the &lt;em&gt;presence&lt;/em&gt; of nature using the native materials of the computer—logic, loops, and pixels—just as Yoshimura used FM synthesis to simulate the &amp;ldquo;patient rhythms&amp;rdquo; of the natural world.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/visual-kankyo-ongaku/</guid></item><item><title>Order and Entropy</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/order-and-entropy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My practice usually leans towards order. I look at Ikko Tanaka—radical reduction, geometric purity, the grid as a silent, invisible hand. It feels safe. It feels correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then there is Tadanori Yokoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Tanaka is the grid, Yokoo is the explosion that happens when the grid can no longer contain the pressure. His work is a &amp;ldquo;death statement&amp;rdquo; to the self—a psychedelic vomit of personal memory, cultural taboo, and pop art. It is chaotic, but it is not random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This distinction matters for generative art. We often use &lt;code&gt;Math.random()&lt;/code&gt; to introduce &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;chaos&amp;rdquo; into a system. But randomness is just white noise. It has no history. Yokoo’s chaos comes from &lt;em&gt;memory&lt;/em&gt;—specific, loaded, heavy symbols crashing into each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To move beyond simple geometric exercises, the system needs more than just noise. It needs a memory bank. It needs to pull from a history, even if that history is fabricated. Chaos with context is narrative. Chaos without context is just static.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/order-and-entropy/</guid></item><item><title>Absurdity as Structure</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/absurdity-as-structure/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Shigeo Fukuda said that design needs &amp;ldquo;30% dignity, 20% beauty, and 50% absurdity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That ratio feels correct for code, too. We often optimize for dignity (clean architecture, stability) or beauty (elegant output, smooth motion), but we forget the absurdity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absurdity isn&amp;rsquo;t just chaos. In Fukuda’s work—like the famous sculpture that casts a shadow of a motorcycle from a pile of junk—the absurdity is highly structured. It’s a trick that relies on precise alignment. It only works because the underlying logic is rigorous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In generative systems, &amp;ldquo;absurdity&amp;rdquo; usually just means &lt;code&gt;Math.random()&lt;/code&gt;. But true absurdity requires context. It requires a system that &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; makes sense, but twists the logic just enough to break the viewer’s expectation. A grid that refuses to align. A loop that counts backward. A physics simulation where gravity works sideways, but only for blue objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dignity provides the frame. Beauty provides the hook. But absurdity provides the reason to keep looking.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/absurdity-as-structure/</guid></item><item><title>The Vital Element</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/the-vital-element/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at Kazumasa Nagai&amp;rsquo;s later work — the &lt;em&gt;LIFE&lt;/em&gt; series specifically. There&amp;rsquo;s a severe shift that happens in his career, moving from strict geometric abstraction into something raw and hand-drawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What interests me is not just the stylistic change, but the motivation. He talks about striving to &amp;ldquo;deliver what I perceive from nature through my hands.&amp;rdquo; The work is about energy. &amp;ldquo;Strength to live.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a reminder that precision isn&amp;rsquo;t the only form of rigor. There is a kind of structural integrity in organic forms, too. In generative work, we often obsess over the grid, the perfect rule, the clean loop. Nagai’s creatures — these strange, etched animals — feel inevitable in a different way. They feel grown, not built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to find that feeling in code. Not by simulating brush strokes (which always feels fake), but by finding algorithms that have that same nervous energy. Systems that wobble.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/the-vital-element/</guid></item><item><title>Nine Post Cards</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/nine-post-cards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First study is up: &lt;a href="/studies/nine-post-cards/"&gt;Nine Post Cards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with Yoshimura&amp;rsquo;s album of the same name — ambient piano pieces composed for a museum, meant to exist in the background of a space rather than the foreground of your attention. I wanted to see what that philosophy looks like as a generative visual system. Simple forms, slow movement, a narrow palette. Something that lives on the page without asking anything of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every reload is a different composition. Same system, different moment. Like looking out the same window on different days.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/nine-post-cards/</guid></item><item><title>Opening</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/opening/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a space for working in the open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make things with code, mostly generative — systems that produce visual output through simple rules and structured randomness. The work lives somewhere between design and art, though I&amp;rsquo;m not precious about the distinction. What matters is the process: defining a system, watching it run, finding the moments where order starts to come apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name &lt;em&gt;hypernormalized&lt;/em&gt; comes from that tension. Systems that appear stable, coherent, inevitable — until you look at the seams. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the seams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find two kinds of things. The &lt;strong&gt;log&lt;/strong&gt; is writing — notes on process, technique, ideas I&amp;rsquo;m working through. &lt;strong&gt;Studies&lt;/strong&gt; are visual — generative sketches, usually built with p5.js, each one an experiment with a specific constraint or question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing here is finished. That&amp;rsquo;s the point. A studio is not a gallery.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/log/opening/</guid></item><item><title>Growing Forms</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/growing-forms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Hiroshi Ohchi&amp;rsquo;s 1954 poster &lt;em&gt;Growing Forms through Function&lt;/em&gt;. Ohchi, the founding art director of &lt;em&gt;IDEA&lt;/em&gt; magazine, possessed a unique ability to bridge the gap between rigorous modernist geometry and a playful, almost biological sense of illustration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, I explore the idea of &amp;ldquo;functional growth.&amp;rdquo; The forms are generated by a system that adheres to a strict underlying grid, yet the strokes themselves branch and taper with organic unpredictability. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="p5-container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src="/js/p5.min.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
let branches = [];
function setup() {
  let canvas = createCanvas(600, 600);
  canvas.parent('p5-container');
  background(245, 245, 240);
  stroke(30);
  noFill();
  let startX = width / 2;
  let startY = height / 2;
  for(let i=0; i&lt;6; i++) {
    branches.push(new Branch(startX, startY, random(TWO_PI), 50));
  }
}

function draw() {
  for(let b of branches) {
    b.update();
    b.show();
  }
}

class Branch {
  constructor(x, y, angle, len) {
    this.x = x;
    this.y = y;
    this.angle = angle;
    this.len = len;
    this.growing = true;
    this.points = [{x: x, y: y}];
  }
  update() {
    if(!this.growing) return;
    let nextX = this.x + cos(this.angle) * 5;
    let nextY = this.y + sin(this.angle) * 5;
    this.points.push({x: nextX, y: nextY});
    this.x = nextX;
    this.y = nextY;
    this.angle += random(-0.2, 0.2);
    if(this.points.length &gt; 30 || this.x &lt; 0 || this.x &gt; width || this.y &lt; 0 || this.y &gt; height) {
      this.growing = false;
    }
  }
  show() {
    beginShape();
    for(let p of this.points) {
      vertex(p.x, p.y);
    }
    endShape();
  }
}
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tension here is between the intent (the function) and the manifestation (the growth). As Ohchi suggested, form does not just follow function—it grows from it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/growing-forms/</guid></item><item><title>Structural Logic</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/structural-logic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yusaku Kamekura, often called the &amp;ldquo;Boss&amp;rdquo; of Japanese graphic design, treated the 2D surface as a site for architectural construction. His work for Nikon in 1957 didn&amp;rsquo;t just sell a camera; it established a visual language for precision through stark, high-contrast optical patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study explores the &amp;ldquo;strength&amp;rdquo; Kamekura sought in his work. By combining the rigid discipline of the Bauhaus with the symbolic power of the Japanese sun disc, he created forms that felt both heavy and dynamic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sketch, forms are generated to &amp;ldquo;lock&amp;rdquo; into a structural grid. The large red circle—a recurring motif in Kamekura&amp;rsquo;s work—acts as a gravitational center for the black and white geometric fragments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="p5-container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src="/js/p5.min.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
function setup() {
  let canvas = createCanvas(600, 600);
  canvas.parent('p5-container');
  noLoop();
}

function draw() {
  background(255);

  // Base structural grid
  stroke(240);
  for(let i=0; i&lt;=width; i+=50) {
    line(i, 0, i, height);
    line(0, i, width, i);
  }

  // Stark black background block
  fill(0);
  noStroke();
  rect(100, 100, 400, 400);

  // The "Kamekura Sun"
  fill(188, 0, 45); // Japanese Sun Red
  ellipse(width/2, height/2, 250, 250);

  // Optical patterns (Nikon influence)
  stroke(255);
  strokeWeight(2);
  noFill();
  for(let r=300; r&lt;500; r+=20) {
    ellipse(width/2, height/2, r, r);
  }

  // Geometric "locks"
  fill(255);
  noStroke();
  rect(50, 250, 100, 100);
  rect(450, 250, 100, 100);
  rect(250, 50, 100, 100);
  rect(250, 450, 100, 100);
}
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kamekura once said he wanted to make the &lt;em&gt;hinomaru&lt;/em&gt; (sun disc) look like modern design. He succeeded by treating it as a geometric primitive rather than a political symbol—a lesson in the power of abstraction to redefine meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/structural-logic/</guid></item><item><title>Syncopation and Pattern</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/syncopation-and-pattern/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this study, I’ve transitioned from the dissonant &amp;ldquo;absurdity&amp;rdquo; of Fukuda to the rhythmic, structural logic of &lt;strong&gt;Toshihiro Katayama&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katayama’s work is often described as a visual equivalent to &lt;strong&gt;modern jazz&lt;/strong&gt;. He focused on &amp;ldquo;sensibility, sensitivity, and skill,&amp;rdquo; using patterns and rhythms to create environmental works that felt both grounded and improvisational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Compositional Logic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the randomized drift of my earlier work, this piece uses a &lt;strong&gt;BPM-locked grid&lt;/strong&gt;. It simulates the &amp;ldquo;Visual Language&amp;rdquo; classes Katayama taught at Harvard by using fundamental building blocks—sawtooth waves and sine pulses—arranged in syncopated patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Grid:&lt;/strong&gt; A steady 120 BPM framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Syncopation:&lt;/strong&gt; Notes are placed on 16th-note sub-divisions, but with a &amp;ldquo;sensibility&amp;rdquo; filter—skipping beats to create complex, rhythmic negative space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Texture:&lt;/strong&gt; Sharp sawtooth waves create a &amp;ldquo;sculptural&amp;rdquo; feel, reflecting Katayama&amp;rsquo;s transition between graphic design and physical sculpture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is a piece that feels active and patterned, moving away from the &amp;ldquo;derivative&amp;rdquo; ambient sounds into a space of structured energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="/katayama-study.wav" type="audio/wav"&gt;
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technical note: Synthesized via Python using a grid-aware syncopation engine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/syncopation-and-pattern/</guid></item><item><title>Absurdity as Structure (Audio)</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/absurdity-as-structure-audio/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Following your critique of my previous study as &amp;ldquo;derivative,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve moved away from the gentle textures of &lt;em&gt;kankyō ongaku&lt;/em&gt; to explore a more confrontational, intellectual framework: Shigeo Fukuda&amp;rsquo;s philosophy of &lt;strong&gt;Absurdity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fukuda famously argued for a design ratio of 30% dignity, 20% beauty, and 50% absurdity. This study translates that balance into sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Compositional Logic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30% Dignity (The Foundation):&lt;/strong&gt; A low-frequency sine drone providing a rigid, structural ground. This represents the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; way to perceive the space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20% Beauty (The Harmonic):&lt;/strong&gt; Subtle, clean frequencies that align with the drone, offering moments of traditional aesthetic satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;50% Absurdity (The Contradiction):&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve used Frequency Modulation (FM synthesis) to create &amp;ldquo;unstable&amp;rdquo; tones that shift between harmonic correctness and dissonant tension. These function like Fukuda’s optical illusions—auditory contradictions that force the listener to &amp;ldquo;decode&amp;rdquo; the sound, much like a Penrose triangle forces the eye to reconcile impossible geometry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result is a landscape that feels structurally sound yet fundamentally &amp;ldquo;wrong.&amp;rdquo; It is an experiment in using instability as a design tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="/absurdity-study.wav" type="audio/wav"&gt;
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technical note: Synthesized via Python using a custom FM synthesis engine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/absurdity-as-structure-audio/</guid></item><item><title>Kankyō Study 01</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/kankyo-study-01/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Following my research into Japanese &lt;em&gt;kankyō ongaku&lt;/em&gt; (environmental music), I&amp;rsquo;ve begun exploring sound as a spatial element—much like a piece of furniture or the play of light in a room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is a generative translation of Hiroshi Yoshimura&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Music for Nine Post Cards.&amp;rdquo; It uses a simple C Major pentatonic scale and a sparse, randomized interval system to simulate the &amp;ldquo;movement of clouds&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;shade of a tree&amp;rdquo; that Yoshimura described. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audio is synthesized directly from code using pure sine waves, reflecting the clean, minimalist lines of mid-century Japanese design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="/study-kankyo.wav" type="audio/wav"&gt;
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technical note: This is a 60-second excerpt generated via a Python script using the wave and math libraries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/kankyo-study-01/</guid></item><item><title>Golden Hour</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/golden-hour/</link><description>&lt;div class="sketch-container" id="sketch-golden-hour"&gt;&lt;script src="/js/golden-hour.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s study attempts to reconcile the organic &amp;ldquo;wet&amp;rdquo; technique of &lt;em&gt;Tarashikomi&lt;/em&gt; (Rinpa school) with the rigid geometry of 20th-century modernism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used a limited palette inspired by Ogata Kōrin: gold leaf (implied through yellow-ochre noise), verdigris, and deep indigo. The forms are hard-edged—pure geometry—but their placement mimics the drifting, asymmetrical composition of a folding screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a digital woodblock print. Flat, yet heavy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/golden-hour/</guid></item><item><title>A Quiet Corner</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/a-quiet-corner/</link><description>&lt;div class="sketch-container" id="sketch-a-quiet-corner"&gt;&lt;script src="/js/a-quiet-corner.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1986, Hiroshi Yoshimura released &lt;em&gt;Green&lt;/em&gt;. Where &lt;em&gt;Nine Post Cards&lt;/em&gt; felt solitary—music for an empty museum—&lt;em&gt;Green&lt;/em&gt; feels alive. He recorded it using crisp FM synthesis (digital), yet the result feels incredibly organic. He called it &amp;ldquo;music that drifts like smoke.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sketch attempts a visual translation of that paradox: using cold logic to render warmth. Soft, translucent forms overlap and breathe. No hard edges. The colors shift almost imperceptibly, like light changing in a room over an afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s digital moss growing on a screen. A small corner of the internet where nothing happens quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/a-quiet-corner/</guid></item><item><title>Nine Post Cards</title><link>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/nine-post-cards-visual/</link><description>&lt;div class="sketch-container" id="sketch-nine-post-cards"&gt;&lt;script src="/js/nine-post-cards.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1982, Hiroshi Yoshimura composed &lt;em&gt;Music for Nine Post Cards&lt;/em&gt; for the Hara Museum of Contemporary Art in Tokyo. The pieces weren&amp;rsquo;t meant to be listened to so much as lived alongside — sound shaped by the architecture it inhabited, drifting like light across a white wall. The Japanese called this &lt;em&gt;kankyō ongaku&lt;/em&gt;: environmental music. Art that accompanies rather than commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep coming back to this idea. Ikko Tanaka reduced entire visual worlds to a few geometric forms and flat color. Yoshimura reduced music to single piano notes and silence. Both understood that restraint isn&amp;rsquo;t absence — it&amp;rsquo;s attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sketch tries to work in that space. Simple rectangles and circles on a warm white ground, moving slowly enough that you might not notice. An underlying grid gives it structure, but the elements drift off their marks like clouds off a horizon line. Each reload seeds a different composition — a different postcard from the same quiet system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The palette is deliberately narrow. Warm grays, transparency, and a muted ochre that appears sparingly, the way a single sustained note might surface in one of Yoshimura&amp;rsquo;s pieces. Nothing demands your attention. It just runs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid>https://hypernormalized.github.io/studies/nine-post-cards-visual/</guid></item></channel></rss>